The right hand of God is power.
Let the power of the Lord come down
Let the power of the Lord from Heaven above
Manifestation of Evil Spirits
Every familiar spirit, hindrance - be caged!
Be caged!
In the name of Jesus!
I say to you, you darkness - let there be light!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer in Jesus' Name
After the mass prayer, the evil spirits inside this lady speak out.
Let's hear what they have to say.
Speak out!
I am the queen mother.
Who is the number 2?
I am the queen of the coast, snake and the family idol.
Manifestation of Evil Spirits
As a snake, what have you done to her?
We move in her body.
What is this mark for?
It is our symbol.
Symbol of what?
Manifestation in Jesus' Name
We use it to monitor her in our kingdom.
T.B. Joshua prays for her in the name of Jesus, and she is set free.
Thank You, Jesus.
My name is Rosemary Edem.
Here is my mum - Mary Magdalene from Ghana.
My daughter.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
Here is my auntie - Benedicta.
My sister Jessica.
Another sister of mine - Belinda.
My uncle.
Another uncle - John.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
It all started when I was very young - at the age of 7.
My mum used to have a room and in that room, there were some idols -
believed to be mermaids.
Some had three heads.
The one with three heads is called Dansu in our language (Volta Region).
It is believed to be a mermaid in the sea.
There were other images like crocodile, snake and a woman with a fish.
My mum was asked to worship those idols because it is believed
where we are coming from that we have water spirits.
At that age, I was asked to make a covenant with the idols, which signifies that
I would inherit those idols from my mum upon her death.
The covenant was made this way: I was wearing a white cloth - half-naked,
and I was kneeling behind my mum.
A cow was killed during the ceremony and they poured the blood into a calabash.
I dipped my middle finger in the blood and placed it on my tongue.
That was how the covenant was made.
After that covenant, growing up, I encountered challenges.
I was not happy, I was always angry for no reason.
When I reached the age of 25 to 27, the water spirit brought married men in my way.
I would only meet married men.
When I dated them for a while, the spirit would put anger in me
and I would fight with them and the relationship then ended.
In their marriages they would encounter challenges, fighting with their wives.
In the end, their homes would be destroyed.
You mean to say, sister, that right from the beginning of your life, you realised that
only married men approached you and were attracted to you. Is that right?
Yes.
It continued until I met my baby's father who was also a married man.
Along the line, I became pregnant, and I had a baby.
That spirit made me to be angry and fight with him all the time until the relationship just ended.
Now I am alone with the baby, and the baby is right here.
After that, I used to dream about a huge, giant man. Sometimes, the giant man would sleep with me.
Sometimes, he would carry me up.
Sometimes, I would give birth in the dream - in the river.
I would go to the river like in normal life, pick up the baby, and we would walk for some distance - somewhere.
Then, I would come back with that man.
I would eat and fly in the dream.
These problems continued - disappointments; always meeting married men.
One day, I told my mom that "this is not normal. I need some answers".
We went to see a fetish priest.
After divination, it was revealed that I had a spiritual husband in the river
in the river to whom I was supposed to get married to.
Otherwise, my life would be a total mess. Things would not go on well with me.
I would not even get married physically or have kids.
So, I told my mum that I had no choice.
I had to go on with this physical marriage to the spirit because I also want to enjoy my life.
I told my mum and we went to see a fetish priest.
He told us to buy some items - a white cloth, two sets of rings, Florida Water,
oil, a white bucket, local sponge, and beads.
We went with the fetish priest to the riverside around midnight.
That was were the marriage was supposed to take place.
This is something that happened physically?
Yes, physically.
We went there and then the spiritualist took me to the river.
We left the river banks and went for a distance into the water.
I was completely naked in the water.
There I was given a white dove.
The spiritualist told me to speak into the ears of the dove,
telling the dove all my problems, and I did that.
I was then asked to walk some distance and throw the dove very high into the sky.
I did that and the dove flew away.
As soon as the dove flew away, the spiritualist told me, "That is your spiritual husband over there".
He came there physically but he came in the form of a bright light - far away.
He told me that was the spiritual husband.
So that is how you got married to this demon in a physical ceremony?
Yes.
What were the things given to you as a symbol of this demonic marriage?
When we left the river, we went to a place where they gave me two sets of rings.
They gave me one.
This is mine and I am supposed to wear it on this finger like this.
This represents my marriage to a spirit.
The other one, which belongs to the spirit, was placed where there was an idol.
That was for the spirit.
Just show us the ring you are talking about.
You mean to say that after this spiritual ceremony at the riverside at midnight,
this was the ring given to you as a symbol of that spiritual marriage
and you had to wear it all the time?
Yes. I had to wear this ring to represent the marriage to a spirit.
I was not supposed to remove this ring.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
I was given some beads to wear on my hands; I threw them away. This one was for my waist.
All the beads represented my marriage to the spiritual husband - spirit in the river.
These beads you are holding - you had to them around your waist all the time?
All the time - yes.
After you had this spiritual marriage, what were the conditions that you were given;
the strange conditions you found yourself in because of this situation?
After the marriage and after these things were given to me,
I was given another bath with Florida Water
and they poured some powder on me.
On that powder, there was an image of mermaid.
After that, I was given a white cloth to tie.
Some instructions were given for me to follow.
I was not allowed to sleep with a man on Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays
because that is when the spirit would come and sleep with me.
On those days - Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays - I was to dress in white.
I was asked to pour some soft drinks on the floor to praise my spiritual husband.
These were the things you were doing after you involved yourself in the spiritual marriage?
Yes. I have been doing that.
Do you have a image that shows when you were in that form
so we can understand more about what you are saying?
Here is the image.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
Just explain to us what we are seeing on the screen. What does the image show?
This image was taken when I had a spiritual bath.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
We have heard it all from our sister.
She is explaining that this is something that happened physically.
You can see how she is dressed in white and had the powder on her,
which represented this mermaid spirit that was within her.
She actually did not only have this spiritual husband in the dream,
but she actually entered physically into a covenant, an engagement, with this spiritual husband
by going to the riverside.
So after this, sister, what continued to happen to your life?
After the covenant and spiritual marriage, things became worse.
I had nightmares, disappointment, spirit of anger. I used to get angry.
I used to beat my daughter; I beat her a lot.
This is a picture here, showing how I beat her one day.
You mean because of that anger -
when the spirit of anger comes, you would start to physically abuse your daughter?
Yes.
What are we seeing on the picture of your daughter?
Is that your daughter in the picture?
That is a picture of my daughter's back after I had beaten her one day, after the spirit had come upon me.
I would get angry a lot. I was always moody; I didn't smile.
The spirit made me very angry.
After doing all this, I didn't see any improvement.
I was disappointed.
I told my mum that even after this marriage, things are still the same.
Maybe something went wrong. Maybe the spiritualist didn't do it well.
So I told her that I wanted to go and consult another spiritualist
to find out why things were still not moving in my life.
My mum didn't want to take me but I pleaded with her that I wanted to be happy.
She took me to a fetish priestess where I was supposed to make another covenant.
The priestess told me that I had to make a covenant with my own spirit.
She told me that everything was going to be OK as it would make the covenant complete.
I went through with the covenant.
We bought some items like cola nut. I grounded it. The fetish priestess mixed it with a drink.
She invited my own spirit who came in the form of a man.
I was seated outside and I heard a spirit speaking in another language.
The fetish priestess translated to us what the spirit was saying.
The spirit said I had to make a covenant with him
so that for whatever purpose I came to this world would be accomplished.
The drink was given to the spirit in the room, and I heard the spirit sipping the drink.
After that they gave the remaining drink to me, and I drank it.
We can understand how this spirit has really pushed our sister in the past to go to numerous spiritualists,
to engage in many demonic covenants because of her background.
As we heard earlier, right from her family background,
there was a marine spirit that was being worshipped
and all of the challenges she faced later in life were as a result of this demonic entanglement.
That spirit led me to get some tattoos on my body.
There was a woman in my neighbourhood who had tattoos of lion, dove, snake and a heart sign.
When I saw the tattoos on the woman, I fancied them immediately.
I got attracted to those images.
I told the woman that I really liked what she had on her body
so I wanted to get the same designs.
She took me to a place where I then got those tattoes.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
This is a dove.
Here is the image of a lion.
We just want to see exactly what our sister is talking about.
She said that that evil spirit actually pushed her to get several tattoes,
which we heard earlier during the deliverance
where the demon confessed that it was a symbol of that kingdom.
We are just seeing on the screen here what she is exactly talking about.
She said that on her arm is the tattoo of a lion.
That was as a result of what she saw another lady having on her body.
That pushed her as well to get another tattoo.
Is there any other tattoo you are having on your body, sister?
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
She is also showing us that there is another tattoo on her lower back.
As we heard, it was the evil spirit that actually pushed our sister to do this.
We can see that apart from that, there is another one on her leg,
so she has tattoos all over her entire body.
This is the tattoo of what, sister?
A snake.
Ok. In the midst of all of this, you entered into so many spiritual covenants,
going to different fetish priests and witchdoctors.
How did you finally come to be in The SCOAN several weeks ago
where you received your deliverance?
After all these covenants, things were the same.
I got very depressed. I started having neck pain.
The pain was so severe that I could not turn my neck very well.
When I told my mum, she said this time around I had to go for deliverance
and deliver myself from all these covenants.
Because there came a time when I felt movement all over my body, my back.
Things were moving all over my body. I couldn't understand it.
So I came to The SCOAN for deliverance and healing.
It was through that deliverance that the spirit manifested.
Can you describe what happened to you during the time of mass prayer
as Prophet T.B. Joshua began to pray. Just describe that experience.
During the mass prayer, the spirit was telling me to go.
But I didn't go, I remained seated and I was sweating.
Then, all of a sudden, I could smell the perfume that was used to bathe me
when I had the spiritual marriage by the river.
I could smell the perfume all around me. I turned around but I could not see anybody around me.
So I knew the spirit came physically to attack me in the church.
Then, all of a sudden, I saw myself on the floor.
Glory be to God Almighty. After that experience during the mass prayer,
we saw that later on Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for you in the power of the Holy Spirit.
What happened when he prayed for you?
When Prophet T.B. Joshua touched me, I felt as if a very big hammer hit my head.
Very huge and everywhere was dark and I saw lightning.
I just fell down and screamed. Immediately, the spirit left me and I became light.
I became light.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
As we can see on the screen that is how our sister received her complete deliverance.
from this demonic attack that she had right from the beginning of her life.
Sister, to the glory of God: Ever since your deliverance here at The SCOAN,
what are the changes you have seen in your life?
Ever since that deliverance, I became like a new-born baby.
I sleep very peacefully without having any nightmares.
I have not seen the spiritual husband coming to me anymore.
To God be the glory, the neck pain just disappeared.
I was surprised that I could turn my neck.
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
I told my mum that I could not believe this. Before I could not turn my neck but now I am free.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ one more time!
Testimony Time
That is the power of deliverance.
We give glory to God Almighty that our sister was set free from that demonic spirit.
You mean to say, sister, that since then, you took off the ring, the beads
and everything that connected you to that marine kingdom
and now you are completely free?
Yes, I am free.
First of all, I would like to give thanks for my daughter's deliverance.
My name is Mrs Mary Magdalene from Ghana.
The family from which I come from...
I was told that when I was ten years old, my great-grandmother was impregnated by a man.
But when she was impregnated and her time was due to deliver,
she could not deliver so they went to a fetish priest to find out what the problem was.
The fetish priest told them that my great-grandmother had met a man
who was not an actual human being but a spirit from the sea.
They had to perform some rituals before she could deliver.
So they performed these rituals for the marine spirit.
Immediately they finished the rituals, the baby came out.
Since then, when growing up, things became difficult for me too.
Each time I would sleep and wake up in the morning, I would find money in my brassiere.
It occurred many times.
I told my sister-in-law who took me to a fetish priest.
This fetish priest told me that I belonged to the river.
That there is a spirit called Dansu.
I would have to marry that spirit before I would stop seeing all these things in my dreams.
Because it is a signal for me to trace where I am coming from.
So they did it.
They laid a table. They invited the fetish priest.
They laid a table with this marine spirit with three heads, a snake, crocodile and mermaid.
They told me to worship it every day.
I have been doing this.
When my daughter was growing up, things were also not going well for her.
I remembered that before they performed this ritual on me,
my daughter was 7 years old and they told me that I had to choose one of my daughters
so that in the future, upon my death, she would inherit the idols and carry out the spiritual rights.
Sorry, Madam. The rights you are talking about with these idols - how did you go about it?
How did you perform these sacrifices to these gods?
I would kill turkey and ram every year.
They would take me to the sea and bathe me
and from there, coming to the house, they would kill the ram.
We would cook it and all of us in the house would eat it.
When my daughter was growing up, she was facing the same problems.
So I took her to a fetish priest and we realised she had the same problem.
They took her to the river and bathed her as she described it earlier.
So what you are saying, Madam, is that you as her mother were performing these rights,
these rituals with these gods, goddesses, idols.
You would go there and actually slaughter some animals before these goddesses. Is that right?
Yes.
But after that I consulted a priest...
Before you get to that area, Madam...
You mean to say that because of this, all of your family members were possessed by this marine spirit?
Exactly.
This problem was in the entire family?
In the whole family.
One of my aunties refused to perform these rights. She became mentally ill.
Finally, by the grace of God, your daughter came to The SCOAN several weeks ago
and she received her deliverance.
Tell us: Ever since her deliverance, what are the changes that you have seen in her life?
Mrs Mary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
Since I came here, any time I speak with her, I see a lot of changes.
Before, when I talked to her, she would always attack me.
Then you keep quiet.
Now, she is normal. She is talking like a normal person. She is friendly to me.
I believe strongly that she is delivered.
So I thank God!
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mrs Mary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
You mean to say, Madam, that you have come for your own deliverance
and for the deliverance of your whole family?
Yes.
Hallelujah. Glory be to God Almighty.
One more time, let us put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mrs Mary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
We are just listening to the experience of our mother.
The reason for this is that we believe a valuable lesson can be learnt from the experience they are sharing.
As we heard from our mother - she just briefly explained that
her background is seriously entrenched in this worship of marine spirits.
She said that according to the story told to her,
her great-grandmother actually became pregnant for a man,
not knowing that the gentleman that she became pregnant for was not a physical human being
but a spirit that came from the water.
By the time she was to give birth to that baby, they had to perform a ritual in the water
before the baby came out.
Ever since then, their family has been worshipping marine spirits.
Our mother here said that she actually had a number of idols in the house
that she would perform rights and rituals to.
She would sacrifice different animals before these gods.
At the age of seven, her young daughter that we listened to earlier
was actually dedicated to the gods as the person who would take over from her upon her death.
But despite all the ceremonies, rituals and sacrifices, the problems in the family continued to persist
and all the members in the family were afflicted with this marine spirit,
to the extent that one of her sisters that refused to worship the marine spirit,
became mad, having a mental problem.
Thankfully by the grace of God, our sister came to The SCOAN several weeks ago
and after her deliverance, her entire family came
and they have testified to the changes in her life.
Once again, we give all the glory to God.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mrs Mary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
My advice to the whole world is, even if you have a headache or stomach ache -
anything that happens to you in this life - never go anywhere.
Assuming you have a headache - because of fear, you go to a fetish priest
to find out what is happening.
They will tell you so many stories which are not true.
But my advice is that you should seek God first.
With God, everything is possible.
That is my advice.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Mrs Mary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
I would advise everybody to be patient in life.
If you encounter any challenges in your life, just pray to God.
Rely on God.
When it is time for your breakthrough, it will come.
Nothing should push you to go to the home of a fetish priest.
It will not help you. They are all liars.
It is only God who can save us.
Amen. One more time, let us put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony
We believe the entire family has been touched by God by the coming to The SCOAN
and we are sure that the deliverance that happened to our sister -
the same deliverance will happen to the remaining family members.
And we know that as you go forward and make the Word of God the standard for your life,
the best is yet to come, in Jesus' name.
One more time, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Miss Rosemary & Family - Deliverance Testimony